Koh, Achim [atç<sup>h</sup>im] is a **researcher**, **developer**, **translator** and **editor**. His work engages the technopolitics of machine learning, digital art, musical interfaces, and the South Korean web. His inprogress thesis is a case study of Google Magenta, in an attempt to contextualize recent industrial interests in musical applications of AI with regards to music technology and capitalism. His work has been exhibited at Seoul Museum of Art; he presented at the Theorizing the Web conference. Often multitasking, he works in English, French, Korean, JavaScript, Python, and R.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2016-2018

## **Designer & Developer**

Tools for Clear Speech, Baruch College, CUNY New York.

Produced new interface for website; designed and implemented web-based audio recorder and video player; implemented new identity.

2013-2014

## Researcher

Making Lab, the 4th Anyang Public Art Project Anyang, South Korea.

Held a versatile position as local team lead for community makerspace including artist research, project management, public outreach, translation, editing, education programming. Part of the 4th APAP, the biggest public art Biennale in South Korea. Collaboration w/ Taeyoon Choi.

2010

### Coordinator

**BEHIVE** Seoul, South Korea.

Played a versatile role including artist research, space management, onsite technical support, event organization, public relations for art gallery BEHIVE. Produced events including concerts by Joo Won Park, Trampoline, 404; live performances by Hang-jun Lee and Hojun Kim.

2009-2012

# Co-creator, Producer, Head Writer & Audio Engineer

recandplay.net Seoul, South Korea.

Played a major role in a team setting from project conception, booking, public relations, writing, audio recording and editing. The project produced 50+ videos aggregating more than 5 million views.

Engaged then-new technologies such as HD video streaming services and portable recording devices. 2007–ongoing

### **Translator & Interpreter**

Written translations and oral interpretations to/from Korean, English, and French for publications, art exhibitions, technical projects, etc.

Specializes in art and critical theory, digital technology, and music.

1 Achim Koh

## **AWARDS & EXHIBITIONS**

- Research Grant (Third Grade). Open Net Research Paper Competition. "Zeroboard, Easy-to-install BBS—Rough sketch for a techno-cultural maker history of the Korean internet." Seoul, South Korea, 2016.
- Korean Internet Tour Guide. SeMA Biennale Mediacity Seoul 2016. Seoul Museum of Art. Seoul, South Korea, 2016.

## SELECT ARTICLES, TEACHING & TALKS

2017

"Machine Learning: A Primer." Workshop. NYCDH Week 2017, New York.

2016

- "Resources for a Critical Machine Learning." Presentation. CUNY IT Conference 2016, New York.
- Koh, Achim, Kang, E Roon, & So, Wonyoung. "Zeroboard, Easy-to-install BBS—Rough sketch for a techno-cultural maker history of the Korean internet." Open Net Research Paper Competition, Seoul, 2016.

Public events at Mediacity Seoul 2016 NERIRI KIRURU HARARA, Seoul:

"Alternate Paths." Round-table.

"Korean Internet Tour Day." Lecture.

- "Techno-culture Research Methods." Seminar. Seun Living Lab x Unmake Lab, Seoul.
- "The Year 2015 in Korean Online Feminism: Two Movements Against Misogyny."

  Presentation. *Theorizing the Web 2016*, New York.
- "The Wreckages in the South Korean Web." Presentation. *Mapping Memory Conference*, New York City.

-2015

- "Simple music instrument with openFrameworks." Workshop. ITP Camp, New York, 2015.
- "Maker Culture and Possibilities of Citizen Participation." Lecture. KAIST Creative Lab for Culture Technology Venturing, Seoul, 2013.
- "Open Source Hardware Workshop." Workshop series (assistant instructor). NEXON Computer Museum NCM Lab 3.0, Jeju, 2013.
- "Music, Video, and Blog with recandplay." Lecture series at MEDIACT, Seoul, 2011.

### **SELECT TRANSLATIONS**

2017

Beck, Jeesook. "Caressing The Skin of History." *Korea Artist Prize 2017*. Seoul: National Museum of Modern and Contemporary Art, 2017.

Curator's statement for The Other Face of the Moon at Asia Culture Center, Gwangju, 2017.

Kim, Hyunjin. Sasanggye-related research text for *Parapolitics: Cultural Freedom and the Cold War* at Haus der Kulturen der Welt, Berlin, 2017.

Kang, E Roon et al. Seoul Libre Maps. https://medium.com/seoul-libre-maps. 2017.

2016

Ham, Yang Ah. The Village. Forthcoming. (co-translation)

2 Achim Koh

Kim, Lynn et al. *Touch Type: Research on Body and Typography*. Seoul: Korea Craft & Design Foundation, 2016.

Seoul Museum of Art. SeMA Biennale Mediacity Seoul 2016: NERIRI KIRURU HARARA. Seoul: Seoul Museum of Art, 2016. (co-translation)

Kang, E Roon, Koh, Achim and So, Wonyoung. *Korean Internet Tour Guide*. http://k-www.kr/en. 2016.

Choi, Taeyoon et al. 우리가 세운 벽을 탈(脫)학습하기. Seoul, 2016. (co-translation)

Ji-Hyun Park, Park Hyun-jung, Woo Ahreum. "Correspondence." COULD BE NO.1: Trios of Guides. Seoul: Seoul Museum of Art, 2016. link

-2015

Choi, Taeyoon & Kang, E Roon. *In Search of Personalized Time*. Website and video documentation. http://i-s-o-p-t.com/. 2015.

마리 조제 오데르세. 나를 믿는 기술. Seoul: Kaema Kowon, 2010.

실비 보시에. 죽음, 왜 쉬쉬하지? Seoul: Kaema Kowon, 2009.

티에리 타옹. 예비 아빠의 철학. Seoul: Kaema Kowon, 2008.

크리스토프 라무르. 걷기의 철학. Seoul: Kaema Kowon, 2007.

## **EDUCATION**

In progress

M.A. in Liberal Studies; Interactive Technology and Pedagogy certificate program. The Graduate Center, CUNY, New York City.

2015

The School for Poetic Computation, New York City.

2008

B.A. in Mass Communication. Yonsei University, Seoul.

#### SELECT SKILLS

Languages: Fluent in English, French, Korean, JavaScript, Python, R.

**Machine Learning:** Able to design and conduct experiments and complete workflows using scikit-learn and TensorFlow; able to build browser-based user interfaces using JavaScript.

**Data Mining:** Comfortable scraping, analyzing & visualizing data using REST APIs, headless browsers, scikit-learn and p5.js.

**Web Development:** Comfortable building static websites and/or work in frontend using HTML5, Jekyll and Git.

**Creative Computing:** Familiarity with audiovisual programming frameworks, including Processing, p5.js, Wekinator, Pure Data and openFrameworks. Knowledge of live coding platforms including Sonic Pi.

**Audio Engineering:** Multiyear experience in field and small studio recording, audio editing. Deep familiarity with Ableton Live and Audacity.

Physical Computing: Knowledge of electronics, Arduino, Raspberry Pi.

3 Achim Koh